Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is Conan's 100th episode! My first love is about to be found out!
!اليوم يصل كونان حلقة بثّه المئة! حُبي الأوّل على وشك أن يُكشف
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Thanks for offering to clean Shinichi's house, Ran-kun.
شكراً يا ران-كن على تفضّلك بتنظيف منزل شينتشي
It's no problem! We have nothing to do anyway!
ليست مشكلة، فلا شيء لدينا لنفعله
"We"?
لدينا؟
Don't decide these things on your own!
!لا تقرّري الأمور من تلقاء نفسك
But it will turn into a ghost house if we don't clean it...
لكن قد يتحوّل إلى منزل أشباح ...إذا لم ننظّفه
Oh well.
حسناً، لا بأس
Shinichi must be happy to have such a thoughtful girlfriend as you!
لا بدّ أنّ شينتشي بغاية السعادة لامتلاكه حبيبةً لطيفة مثلك
You're so silly!
...ليس حقّاً
Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
ألا توافقني يا كونان-كن؟
Y-Yeah.
بـ-بلى
You jerk...
...أيّها الوغد
Well, we're off, Doc!
سنذهب إذاً يا بروفسور
Okay! We're counting on you!
!أجل، أعتمد عليكم
Right!
!حسناً
You'll pay for this.
سأتذكّر هذا
You're not thinking of cleaning the entire house, are you, Ran?
لا تفكّرين بتنظيف هذا المنزل الكبير بأسره، صحيح يا ران؟
Well, let's do as much as we can for today.
حسناً، لنقم بما يسعنا اليوم
Eh? Does that mean we're going to clean all day?
ماذا؟ أتقصدين أنّنا سننظّف طوال اليوم؟
Yeah. That's the plan.
أجل، كانت تلك نيّتي
Sheesh!
...يا إلهي
How did Sonoko-sama get stuck cleaning Shinichi-kun's house
لمَ تنظّف سونوكو-ساما منزل شينتشي-كن
on such a nice Sunday?
في يوم أحد صحوٍ كهذا؟
You could've just ignored it, yet you went and got Doc's spare key!
كان بإمكانك تجاهله وحسب، لكنّك ذهبتِ !للبروفسور وطلبتِ المفتاح البديل حتّى
Sorry! I just figured the place was covered in dust
آسفة، اعتقدتُ أنّ المكان سيكون مليئاً بالغبار
and that it'd be hard to clean alone...
فتنظيفه بمفردي أمرٌ صعب
Yeah, yeah.
حسناً، حسناً
Oh, Sonoko. You should dust the bookcases before sweeping.
سونوكو، عليك تنظيف رفوف الكتب قبل المسح
Eh?
ماذا؟
It's like they say, you should clean from the top down.
تعرفين، يُقال أنّ التنظيف يجب أن يبدأ من الأعلى
Plus, you're supposed to follow the tiles when sweeping the floor!
!كما عليك اتّباع مربّعات البلاط عند مسح الأرض
You sound like such an old hag...
...تتكلّمين كمُسنّة
Girls these days are supposed to be crazy about catching men
يُفترض أن تهتمّ فتيات هذه الأيام بصيد الرجال
and experiencing pure love, first love, and all that...
...وتجربة الحُبّ الصافي، والحُب الأوّل وما إلى ذلك
Yet here I am, getting covered in dust for that mystery dweeb...
لكنّي هنا تحت أكوام الغبار ...لأجل مهووس التحرّي ذاك
I'm oh-so-pathetic.
أنا تعيسة حقّاً
So sorry for the trouble, you two!
اعذراني
Say. Speaking of first love...
...إذاً، بذكر الحُب الأوّل
Yeah?
أجل؟
What do you suppose Shinichi's first love was like?
كيف كان حُب شينتشي الأوّل يا ترى؟
He must've had a love or two by now!
لا بدّ أنّه مرّ بتجربة حُب !واحدة أو اثنتين
I dunno. He's super-dull in the head when it comes to things like that.
لا أدري، إنّه بليدٌ عندما يتعلّق الأمر بهذه المواضيع
But, given his hot mother, it was probably a TV idol, or...
،لكن بوضع أمّه الجميلة في الاعتبار ...فربما كانت فنّانةً على التلفاز، أو
Come to think of it, you've always been together since you were kids.
بالمناسبة، كنتما معاً طوال الوقت في صغركما، صحيح؟
Y-Yeah...
...بلى
What's more, you're thoughtful and strong...
فوق ذلك، أنتِ لطيفة وقويّة
Who knows, maybe you're his first love!
!قد تكونين أنت حبّ شينتشي-كن الأوّل
Eh?!
ماذا؟
Hey, now!
!أنت، أنت
Yeah, right! We only played together when we were kids!
مستحيل، كنّا نلهو لا أكثر عندما كنّا صغاراً
But then there's your precedent, too.
...لكن هناك علاقتك السابقة أيضاً يا ران
Huh? Isn't Shinichi-kun your first love?
ماذا؟ ألم يكن شينتشي-كن حبّك الأوّل؟
H-Hold on! Don't make stuff up!
!ا-انتظري! لا تختلقي من تلقاء نفسك
Oh? Your bashfulness says otherwise, Girl of Twenty Faces.
ماذا؟ احمرارك يظهر خلاف ذلك أيّتها الفتاة ذات العشرين وجهاً
Knock it off, Sonoko! Before I get mad!
!يكفي يا سونوكو! توقّفي وإلّا سأغضب
S-Seriously?
صـ-صدقاً؟
Huh? Who could that be?
ماذا؟ من قد يكون؟
You're so dumb! It's obviously Shinichi-kun!
يا لحماقتك، إنّه شينتشي-كن بالطبع
No, I kind of doubt that.
لا، ذلك مستحيل
Why would he ring the doorbell to his own house?
لكن هل سيقرع الجرس قبل دخول منزله؟
He probably heard about us from the doc and wants to surprise us!
!لا بدّ أنّه سمع أمرنا من البروفسور وأراد مفاجأتنا
It's not me...
...ليس صحيحاً
B-But Shinichi didn't say anything about coming home...
لـ-لكن لم يقل شينتشي شيئاً عن العودة للبيت
What're you so embarrassed about? Hurry and see him!
!ما الذي يحرجك هكذا؟ اذهبي واستقبليه
He's your first love prince, isn't he?
إنّه أمير حبّك الأوّل، أليس كذلك؟
I'm telling you, it's not like that!
!أخبرتك! الأمر ليس هكذا
Oh?
ماذا؟
Are you a friend of Kudo-kun?
أأنتِ صديقة لكودو-كن؟
Y-Yes...
أجل
Huh?! Isn't she...
...ماذا؟ أليست هذه
Umm, are you Asami-senpai?
المعذرة، أأنتِ أسامي سينباي؟
Yes.
بلى
You know her, Sonoko?
تعرفينها يا سونوكو؟
What are you saying?
ما الذي تقولينه؟
She was student body president during our first year of middle school!
كانت رئيسة مجلس الطلبة عندما كنّا !في السنة الأولى في متوسّطة تيتان
You know! Uchida Asami-senpai!
!أوتشيدا أسامي سينباي
Uchida Asami (18) Toto Univ. Literature Dept., 1st Year
(أوتشيدا أسامي (18 طالبة سنة أولى، كليّة الأدب في جامعة توتو
Oh. So Kudo-kun has been away for a while on some cases?
هكذا إذاً، كودو-كن غائبٌ عن منزله لفترة بسبب بعض القضايا؟
So that's why I always got the answering machine.
لذا كانت تجيبني آلة الردّ باستمرار
I'm sorry, it's almost like I've asked you to clean...
المعذرة، أشعر كأنّي جعلتك ...تساعديننا في التنظيف
It's no problem at all! I had nothing else to do!
ليست مشكلة، فلا شيء لديّ لأفعله
Anyways, Senpai. Why did you want to see Shinichi-kun?
بالمناسبة يا سينباي، لمَ أردتِ لقاء شينتشي-كن؟
My friends in the university's mystery club are going to rent a lodge
سيستأجر أصدقائي في نادي التحرّي في الجامعة نُزلاً
and hold a birthday party for me this weekend.
ويقيمون حفلةً لعيد ميلادي نهاية هذا الأسبوع
I really wanted to invite Kudo-kun.
أردتُ دعوة كودو-كن
Seeing as he's a great detective and an old soccer club teammate.
بما أنّه متحرٍّ شهير وزميل قديم لي في نادي كرة القدم لمتوسّطة تيتان
But I sent the letter quite a while back...
...لكنّي أرسلت الرسالة قبل فترة
Did he say anything before he left home?
لم يقل شيئاً قبل مغادرته منزله؟
Not really...
...ليس تماماً
Oh no! I forgot!
!تبّاً! نسيت
Oh. I was sure he would come.
فهمت، كنت متأكّدة أنّه سيأتي
I wonder if he forgot about that confession four years ago...
أتساءل إذا نسي ذاك الاعتراف ...قبل أربعة أعوام
Confession?
الاعتراف؟
Though I guess I can't blame him for forgetting.
رغم أنّي لا أستطيع استغراب نسياته
First loves are bound to fade away with time...
...فزواله مع الوقت
She was Shinichi's first love?
كانت حُبّ شينتشي الأوّل؟
Now I get it. It all makes sense.
فهمت، توضّحت الصورة لي
Everyone was talking about it our first year of middle school.
كان الجميع يتكلّمون في سنتنا الأولى في المتوسّطة
Supposedly a first-year boy made a pass at Asami-senpai.
عن مغازلة صبيّ في السنة الأولى لأسامي سينباي
So that daredevil was actually Kudo Shinichi, huh?!
!وكان ذاك المُتجرّئ هو كودو شينتشي إذاً؟
It wasn't like that. It was an actual confession.
لم تكن مغازلة! بل اعترافاً حقيقيّاً
Uh oh!
!هذا سيّئ
And then it--
...ثمّ
Uhh, say!
!المعذرة
If Shinichi-niichan won't go, why not ask someone else?
،إذا كان شينتشي-نيتشان لن يأتي فلمَ لا تقومين بدعوة شخص آخر
That's an idea.
معك حقّ
Then how about us?
ماذا عنّا إذاً؟
We've solved a few cases ourselves, you know!
!حللنا بضعة قضايا بدورنا
Hold on, Sonoko!
مهلك يا سونوكو
Come on! We might be able to catch some lively Toto boys!
أين المشكلة؟ قد نستطيع الإيقاع !ببعض شباب توتو الحيويين
Yes. I think my male friends would love having high school girls attend.
أجل، قد يسرّ أصدقائي الشبّان إذا حضرت فتيات في الثانويّة
Plus, if you invite us, there's no question that he'll come too!
كما أنّه بدعوتك لنا، فسيظهر ذاك الشخص !أيضاً بلا شك
"He"?
ذاك الشخص؟
S-Sonoko! You don't mean...
...سـ-سونوكو، أتقصدين
Yep! The great detective who needs no introduction!
!أجل، المتحرّي العظيم الغنّي عن التعريف
A get-together of Toto University's mystery study club?
لقاء لنادي دراسة التحرّي لجامعة توتو؟
Forget it!
!انسوا الأمر
I can't allow you to go to a sleepover without any real adults!
!لا يمكنني السماح لأطفال بالمبيت خارجاً لوحدهم
But you're invited too, Dad.
لكنّك مدعوّ أيضاً يا أبي
I'm busy! I don't have time to mess with stuff like that!
!أنا مشغول! لا وقت لديّ لهذا العبث
Yeah. As a great detective, you can't relax on a weekend.
معك حقّ، لا يمكنك يا عمّ بصفتك متحرّياَ عظيماً اللهو في عطلة نهاية أسبوع
But for the mystery study club, Mori Kogoro-san is almost like a god.
،لكن بالنسبة لنادي دراسة المتحرّي موري كوغورو-سان أشبه بإله لهم
How they'd all like to hear from the peerless detective!
!جميعهم متشوّقون لسماع قصص المتحرّي منقطع النظير
Not to mention all the pretty girls who'll be there,
كما أنّه ستحضر فتيات جميلات كثيرات بمن فيهنّ
including Uchida Asami-senpai, who holds the title of Miss Toto!
أوتشيدا أسامي سينباي التي تحمل !لقب آنسة توتو
M-Miss Toto?
آ-آنسة توتو؟
But if you're busy, we'll accept that we can't go either...
...لكن إذا كنت مشغولاً، فسنتخلّى عن فكرة الذهاب
Well, I'm sure I can somehow rearrange my busy schedule
حسناً، ربما يمكنني إعادة ترتيب أشغالي
to go with you as your chaperone.
فسأرافقكم بصفتي وصيّكم
Besides, I wouldn't want to disappoint all the promising youngsters
كما أنّي سأشعر بالأسف إذا خيّبتُ آمال الشبّان
of this mystery study club!
!الواعدين لنادي دراسة التحرّي
If my stories about the cases I've solved can help them in any way,
إذا كانت قصصي عن القضايا التي حللتها ،قد تفيدهم بأيّ شكل
it may be my duty as a great detective to assist!
!فواجبي كمتحرٍّ عظيم مساعدتهم
What a predictable personality...
...يا للشخصيّة سهلة الفهم
Miss Toto...
...آنسة توتو
Alright! We're finally here!
!حسناً، وصلنا أخيراً
So, where is the lodge?
إذاً، أين النُزل؟
Let's see...
...حسناً
The bus stop is here, so we go up and right...
...محطّة توقّف الحافلة هنا، لذا نصعد ثم نذهب يميناً
Over there!
!هناك
Yeah! I'm gonna get me a Toto boy!
!أجل! سأحصل على شاب توتو
This is a real honor...
...هذا يُشرّفني
...being able to talk and drink with the young minds of Toto U.!
!الكلام والشراب مع عقول جامعة توتو اليافعة
Not only that, you're all good-looking boys and pretty girls!
كما أنّكم جميعاً شبّان وسيمون وفتيات جميلات فوق ذلك
You're too much!
...أنت تبالغ
Sawai Manabu (22) Literature Dept., 4th Year, President of Mystery Study Club
(ساواي مانابو (22 طالب سنة رابعة، كليّة الأدب في جامعة توتو رئيس نادي دراسة التحرّي
Just as I'd expect from a great detective!
كما أتوقّع من المتحرّي العظيم
You know how to control
تعرف كيف تتحكّم بقلوب الناس
people's hearts with words alone!
بمجرّد الكلمات
Hayasaka Tomoko (21) Literature Dept., 4th Year, V.P. of Mystery Study Club
(هاياساكا توموكو (21 طالبة سنة رابعة، كليّة الأدب في جامعة توتو نائبة رئيس نادي دراسة التحرّي
Oh? Are you sure you're not referring to yourself,
ماذا؟ ألا تشير لنفسك؟
playboy Sawai-kun?
أيّها الفتى العابث ساواي-كن
I heard you made a 1st-year girl cry
(نوغوتشي شيباهيسا (20 طالب سنة ثانية، كليّة الأدب في جامعة توتو
Noguchi Shibahisa (20) Literature Dept., 2nd Year Miyazaki Chika (19) Literature Dept., 2nd Year
(ميازاكي تشيكا (19 طالبة سنة ثانية، كليّة الأدب في جامعة توتو
just recently, President!
!في السنة الأولى تبكي
Eh?! Is that true?!
ماذا؟! أهذا صحيح؟
Hey, now! This is Asami's birthday party!
!مهلكما! هذه حفلة عيد ميلاد أسامي اليوم
This isn't the time to put me on trial!
ليس وقت محاكمتي
Yes. And it's also a celebration party
صحيح، كما أنّها للاحتفال بجائزة
for the "Newcomer Award" her novel won the other day.
الوافد الجديد" التي فازت بها روايتها مؤخراً"
That was too bad, Morimoto.
كان ذلك مؤسفاً يا موريموتو
I heard you made it to the final selection, too.
سمعت أنّك وصلت مرحلة الاختيار النهائيّ أيضاً
It couldn't be helped.
لم يكن باليد حيلة
Morimoto Yoshinobu (22) Literature Dept., 3rd Year
(موريموتو يوشينوبو (22 طالب سنة ثالثة، كليّة الأدب في جامعة توتو
I lost to Asami-kun,
،خسرت أمام أسامي-كن
our department's most promising writer!
!أكثر روائيّة واعدة في كليّتنا
Speaking of losing,
،بذكر الخسارة
I lost to her pair in the Literature Department's tennis tournament!
خسرتُ أمام ثنائيّها في مسابقة كرة المضرب لكليّة الأدب
Plus she was named Miss Toto as a freshman!
!وحصلت على لقب "آنسة توتو" في سنتها الأولى
I didn't even make it through the preliminary round...
...أنا لم أصل الجولة التمهيدية حتّى
I really admire her. She can do everything, but doesn't act conceited.
أنا أحترمها حقّاً، فهي لا تظهر أيّ غرور رغم مقدرتها على فعل كلّ شيء
She's also an incredible cook!
!إنّها طاهية بارعة أيضاً
Speaking of which, where is her lemon pie?
...بالمناسبة، فطيرة الليمون خاصّتها ليست هنا
She and Ran are baking it right now!
!تخبزها مع ران الآن
Huh? Asami-kun said she was going to make one and bring it here...
ماذا؟ قالت أسامي-كن أنّها ستخبزها وتجلبها هنا
Sorry for the wait!
!نعتذر على الإطالة
I've been looking forward to this!
!كنّا بالانتظار
Great!
!رائع
Whoa...
...عجباً
It's sloppy...
إنّها متهالكة
Did you really make this, Asami?!
أصنعتِ هذه حقّاً يا أسامي؟
No, I did. It was my first time...
كلا، بل أنا، كانت مرّتي الأوّل
What about your pie, Asami-kun?
ماذا عن فطيرتك يا أسامي-كن؟
I accidentally forgot to bring it.
نسيتُ جلبها
She said she would make one for me, so I asked her to.
فقالت أنّها ستصنع واحدة مكاني، فطلبتُ منها
Geez. Why're you making stuff you don't know how to?
يا إلهي، لمَ تصنعين أشياءً لستِ معتادةً عليها؟
But...
...لكن
Now, now. Save your criticism until after you've tried it.
حسنٌ، حسنٌ، أجّلوا تذمّركم لبعد تذوّقها
Well, go ahead.
هيّا، كلوا
Oh? This pie...
...ماذا؟ هذه الفطيرة
It's a little fragrant, but it's...
...إنّها حلوة قليلاً، لكن
Yummy!
!لذيذة
Me too!
!أنا أيضاً
Let me taste!
!دعوني أجرّب
It really is! This is good!
!معكم حقّ! إنّها جيّدة
Yeah! It looks iffy, but tastes great!
!بالفعل! مظهرها غير جذّاب، لكنّها لذيذة
This is really something!
هذا مُبهر حقّاً
It's good!
!لذيذة، لذيذة
See? With cooking, substance is what matters.
رأيتِ؟ المهمّ في الطبخ هو المحتوى
Once you eat it, you can't tell what it looks like anyway!
بعدما تأكل، لن تعرف كيف كان شكلها حتّى
I've solved every case 100% of the time!
!%تصيب استنتاجاتي في حلّ كلّ القضايا 100
And then you solved the case?!
وحللتِ القضيّة إذاً؟
That's right!
!أجل
I was the one who solved them all.
كنتُ أنا من حلّها كلّها
Wow! What a pretty cake!
!يا للكعكة الجميلة
I went all the way to Ginza to get it!
!ذهبتُ لغينزا لجلبها
I'll find some matches!
سأبحث عن أعواد ثقاب
Oh, that's okay. I borrowed Sawai-kun's lighter.
لا داعي، استعرتُ قدّاحة ساواي-كن
At any age, watching birthday candles being lit is so exciting!
مشاهدة إشعال شمعات كعكة عيد ميلاد !مثيرٌ مهما كان عمرك
Actually, only until you're 20.
ذلك حتّى تصلين العشرين فقط
Eh? Is that so?
ماذا؟ أهذا صحيح؟
Yeah. Once you're over 20, you start to hate each extra candle.
أجل، بعدما تتجاوزين العشرين، تبدئين بكره كلّ شمعة إضافية كلّ سنة
Congratulations. I pray for even greater future success. Toto Literature Prof. Takamura Masao
.مُبارك، أدعو لك بنجاحات مستقبلية أكبر بروفسور كليّة الأدب، جامعة توتو تاكامورا ماساوا
Here it is!
!ها قد أتت
Right at midnight, as promised!
!مع منتصف الليل تماماً، كما اتّفقنا
See? It's good we got a lodge with a fax machine!
رأيتِ؟ استئجار نُزل بآلة فاكس كان خياراً حسناً
Takamura-sensei sent it, Asami!
!وصلت يا أسامي! رسالة تاكامورا سينسي
Huh?
ماذا؟
I think she's asleep.
يبدو أنّها نائمة
No way. What should we do with the cake?
لا يُعقل، ماذا نفعل بهذه الكعكة؟
Aren't we supposed to go to the karaoke place by the station next?
كما ألم نكن سنذهب لحجرة الكاراوكي بقرب المحطّة تالياً؟
Yeah. I already made reservations.
بلى، حجزتُ سلفاً
Oh well.
ليس باليد حيلة
Let's save the cake for tomorrow and go do karaoke ourselves.
لنترك الكعكة للغد ونذهب لحجرة الكاراوكي بمفردنا
Yeah. Nothing else we can do. Let's do that.
،أجل، لا خيار أمامنا فلنفعل ذلك
Karaoke Room
غرفة الكاراوكي
Say, little boy. Want to sing Two-Mix with me next?
اسمع يا فتى، ما رأيك بغناء تو ميكس معي تالياً؟
N-No, I'm fine!
!لـ-لا داعي، سأمتنع
Oh! I'll go next!
!سأغنّي أنا تالياً
What's wrong, Ran?
ما الخطب يا ران؟
Why the glum look?
كان وجهك عابساً
Nothing! I'm not glum at all!
البتّة، لست عابسة
Shall I guess what you're thinking?
هل أخمّن ما الذي كنتِ تفكّرين به؟
Smart and beautiful, a sports warrior and scholar...
...ذكيّة وجميلة، متفوّقة في الرياضة والدراسة
Considerate, popular, and ♪1 at everything...
لطيفة وذات شعبية بين الآخرين وهي الرقم 1 في أيّ ما تفعله
You're thinking about Asami-senpai, aren't you?
أنتِ تفكّرين بأسامي سينباي، أليس صحيحاً؟
Eh?! How could you tell?!
ماذا؟! كيف عرفتِ؟
"I'm no match for her!" is written all over your face!
!"مكتوبٌ على وجهك! "أنا لستُ ندّةً لها
But you can't blame Shinichi-kun for falling for her.
رغم أنّه لا يمكنك لوم شينتشي-كن على الوقوع في حبّها
She was the soccer club's manager.
فقد كانت مديرة كرة القدم
But don't worry about it! She must've rejected him anyway!
!لكن لا تقلقي حيال الأمر! لا بدّ أنّها رفضته
Besides, you're childhood friends!
!كما أنّكما صديقا طفولة
Did you know Shinichi loves lemon pie, Sonoko?
أكنتِ تعرفين يا سونوكو أنّ شينتشي كان يحبّ فطائر الليمون؟
I heard it for the first time today from Asami-senpai.
سمعتُ ذلك لأوّل المرّة اليوم من أسامي سينباي
Eh? Shinichi loves lemon pie?
ماذا؟ يحبّ شينتشي فطيرة الليمون؟
Yes! It's his favorite!
أجل، إنّها المفضّلة له
I told everyone I'd make one because I thought he'd come today,
أخبرتُ الجميع أنّي سأخبز واحدة لأنّني ظننت أنّه سيأتي اليوم
so I brought this.
فجلبتُ هذه
Oh? Shinichi does?
...ماذا؟ شينتشي إذاً
He loves this?
يحبّ هذه؟
I can teach you how to make it if you'd like!
أتريدين أن أعلّمك كيف تصنعينها؟
I don't stand a chance.
لا فرصة لي
She knows so much about Shinichi that I don't.
فهي تعرف أشياء كثيرة عن شينتشي لا أعرفها
Ran...
...ران
C'mon, cheer up! You have your own good qualities too!
!فلتبتهجي يا فتاة! أنتِ تتحلّين بميزاتك الخاصّة
Like what?
مثل ماذا؟
You know! You are strong and brawny 'cause you practice karate!
تعرفين، مهارتك في الكاراتيه !وجسمك الصلب الذي صقلتِه
Come on, now!
!ما هذا الكلام؟
Geez.
...يا إلهي
Oh? There are a lot fewer people.
ماذا؟
Because you were taking so long in the bathroom.
لأنّك أطلت في الخروج من الحمّام
Everyone ran off to the bathrooms by the train station.
فذهب الجميع لدورة المياه عند محطّة القطار
My apologies!
!أعتذر على ذلك
Oh, do you have my cigarettes?
ألديك سجائري؟
I bought some at the convenience store next door!
اشتريتُها من متجر التموينات بالجوار
Oh! They're back!
!لقد رجعوا
Huh? Where's Noguchi-kun?
ماذا؟ أين نوغوتشي-كن؟
He's still walking around the train station to sober up.
لا يزال يمشي أمام المحطّة محاولاً أن يصحو من ثمله
It's already past 3:00...
...تجاوزت الساعة الثالثة
Maybe we should head back. We left the place messy, too.
ألا يجدر بنا العودة؟ فقد تركنا المكان والفوضى تعمّه
Let's tidy up and hit the hay--
...لننظّفه سريعاً ونخلد للـ
H-Hey! Is that a fire?!
ا-انظروا! أليس ذلك حريقاً؟
It is!
!إنّك محق
H-Hold on! Isn't that...
...لـ-لحظة! أيمكن أنّه
...our lodge?!
!نزلنا؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Oh no! Asami-senpai is still in there!
!لا يمكن! لا تزال أسامي سينباي هناك
Let's hurry to the lodge! We might still make it in time!
!لنسرع للنزل بأيّ حال! قد لا نستطيع الوصول في الوقت
Where's the rental car key?!
!أين مفتاح السيّارة المستأجرة؟
Noguchi-kun has it!
بحوزة نوغوتشي-كن
Huh? What's the problem?
ماذا؟ ما الخطب؟
"What's the problem"?! The lodge we rented is on fire!
!أكبر خطب! النزل الذي استأجرناه يحترق
Senpai... Senpai...
...سينباي... سينباي
Please be all right, Asami-senpai!
...أرجوك، فلتكوني بخير
Asami!
!أسامي
Asami-senpai!
!أسامي سينباي
Not good! It doesn't look like she fled outside!
لا جدوى، لا يبدو أنّها هربت خارجاً
D-Don't tell me she's still asleep inside?!
!أ-أيمكن أنّها لا تزال نائمة في الداخل؟
Oh no!
!لا يُعقل
Should we call her on the phone?! She was asleep in the living room!
هل نتّصل بالهاتف ونوقظها؟ فقد كانت !نائمة في غرفة المعيشة
It's no use! It's already burned up!
!لا جدوى، لقد احترق بالفعل
Damn! There's no other choice!
!تبّاً! لا خيار آخر
H-Hey!
!ا-انتظر
I-It's no use! There's no way inside!
!لا-لا جدوى! يستحيل الدخول
No!
!لا يمكن
It's dangerous! Step back!
!هذا خطر! ابتعدي
Asami-senpai!
!أسامي سينباي
Hey! Move that motorcycle! We don't want its gasoline to ignite!
!أنتم! أبعدوا تلك الدرّاجة !ستكون مصيبةً إذا اشتعل البنزين
Right!
!حسناً
Where's the fire truck?!
!لم تصل عربة الإطفاء بعد؟
Huh? My helmet...
...ماذا؟ الخوذة
I'm coming, Senpai!
!أنا قادمة الآن يا سينباي
Hey!
!أنت
What?! Ran and Conan went inside?!
!ماذا؟! دخلت ران وكونان؟
President Sawai followed them, too!
!لحق بهما الرئيس ساواي أيضاً
Those idiots!
!تلك الحمقاء
Senpai!
!سينباي
Senpai! Asami-senpai!
!سينباي! أسامي سينباي
Ran!
!ران
S-Stop, Mori-san!
!كـ-كلا يا موري-سان
Let go! My daughter's in there!
!دعني! ابنتي في الداخل
You'd be in danger too!
!هذا خطرٌ عليك أيضاً
Ran! Ran!
!ران
Ran. Ran!
!ران، ران
Say something, Ran!
!تماسكي يا ران
Sonoko...
...سونوكو
Ran!
!ران
Where are we?
أين نحن؟
A hospital near the lodge. They brought you here afterwards.
مشفى بقرب النزل، نقلوك إلى هنا بعدما حصل
Oh...
...فهمت
What about Asami-senpai?!
!ماذا عن سينباي؟! أسامي سينباي؟
She's sleeping right over there.
إنّها نائمة بجوارك
Other than a little carbon monoxide poisoning, she's just fine!
،تعاني تسمُّم خفيف من أوّل أكسيد الكربون لكن لا خطر على حياتها
Thank goodness! She made it out!
حمداً لله... نجت
What're you talking about? You're the one who saved her!
ما الذي تتكلّمين عنه؟ كنتِ من أنقذتها
You don't remember?
لا تذكرين؟
Nothing at all... I rushed inside without thinking...
البتّة... اندفعتُ للداخل دون تفكير
And Sawai-san led the way to safety after I found her...
وأرشدني ساواي-سان للأمان بعدما وجدتُها
I felt relieved when I got outside, but things got blurry...
شعرتُ بالارتياح بعدما خرجنا، لكن بدأ وعيي يتلاشى
But that was amazing! You busted inside with that helmet on!
!لكنّك كنتِ مذهلة! أخذتِ الخوذة وهببتِ لإنقاذها
Even the firefighters said that it wasn't smart to go into the fire,
،حتّى رجال الإطفاء قالوا أنّ دخولك الحريق كان تهوّراً
but wearing the helmet was the correct thing to do!
!لكنّ ارتدائك للخوذة كان قراراً حكيماً
Oh, that was Conan-kun.
كان ذلك... كونان-كن
He gave it to me just as I was about to run inside.
أعطاني إيّاها عندما كنتُ أهمّ بالدخول
He said I should put it on to protect my hair and face from the flames.
اقترح عليّ ارتداءها لحماية شعري ووجهي من اللهب
Conan-kun did? He's as strange a kid as always...
كونان-كن؟ إنّه طفل غريب كالمعتاد
Yeah. He is.
أجل، معكِ حقّ
So the fire started around 2:50?
بدأ الحريق عند قرابة الثانية وخمسين دقيقة إذاً؟
Yes. People in nearby lodges said they saw smoke.
أجل، قال أشخاص في نُزل مجاور أنّهم رأوا تصاعد الدخان
They thought it was a bonfire at first.
ظنّوا أنّها مجرّد نار تخييم بدايةً
So, do you suspect it was arson?
إذاً، أيمكن أنّها كانت جريمة إحراق؟
No. The fire started in the living room.
كلا، بدأ الحريق في غرفة المعيشة
This cake candle was probably the cause.
كانت شمعة الكعكة هذه هي السبب غالباً
Cake candle?
شمعة الكعكة؟
Yes. It probably fell onto the floor while still lit,
أجل، لعلّها سقطت على الأرض في نقطةٍ ما وهي لا تزال مشتعلة
where it ignited the nearby wrapping paper and curtains.
فانتقلت الشعلة للفائف الهدايا والستائر بالقرب
Why didn't you blow them out?!
!لمَ لم تطفئيها؟
How rude! I did put them out!
!يا للفظاظة! قمت بإطفائها
It couldn't be helped. We were all in a hurry when we left.
لم يكن باليد حيلة، فقد غادرنا في عجلة
I told you, I put them out!
!أخبرتكم أنّي أطفأتها
But the candle did burn down to its base.
لكن كانت الشمعة محترقة لأساسها
If she didn't forget to put it out, there's one other possibility...
...إذا لم تنس إطفاءها، فهناك احتمال آخر
The possibility that Asami-san herself lit the fire in the living room!
أنّ أسامي-سان التي كانت في غرفة !المعيشة قد أضرمت الحريق بنفسها
You can't be serious!
!لا يُعقل
That's absurd! Why would she do that?!
!مستحيل! لمَ قد تفعل ذلك؟
S-Senpai?
سـ-سينباي؟
She's gone?!
!اختفت؟
She must've left while we were getting something to drink!
لا بدّ أنّها غادرت بينما !ذهبنا لجلب شراب
What do we do, Dad?!
ما العمل يا أبي؟
Asami-san was nearly burned to death.
كادت أسامي-سان تحترق موتاً
By one of you here!
!من فِعل أحدكم هنا
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Memories of First Love Case (Part 2)."
قضيّة ذكريات الحب الأوّل (الجزء الثاني)
ALL: Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Fax.
فاكس
On the next episode.
...الحلقة القادمة
We close in on the truth about your first love.
!نقترب من حقيقة الحُب الأوّل
I can already see it.
!إنّه جليّ